Finding Aid for Elizabeth Gaspar Brown Papers, 1933-1995
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Elizabeth Gaspar Brown papers 1933-1995, 1960s-1980s
Brown, Elizabeth Gaspar
2 linear feet
85796 Aa 2
Research associate at the Law School of the University of Michigan. Research associate at the Law School of the University of Michigan. Personal correspondence; research materials relating to her study of Michigan's territorial court system; and other papers concerning Law School history.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Elizabeth Brown (donor no. 3290 ) and came to the library in multiple accessions.
The collection is open to research.
Research associate at the Law School of the University of Michigan.
The Elizabeth G. Brown papers include personal correspondence; research materials relating to her study of Michigan's territorial court system; and other papers concerning Law School history.
Subjects:
Courts--Michigan.; Law.; African American students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Lawyers--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan--Law School.; Women lawyers--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
- Biographical/Personal
  - Vita and miscellaneous biographical information (Box 1)
  - Oral history interview (Box 1)
  - Biographical notes (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous) (Box 1)
  - Photographs (unidentified) (Box 1)
  - Reviews of EB books; EB reviews of others (Box 1)
- Lawyers Club and W. W. Cook
  - "Auditing the Lawyers Club at the University of Michigan" (Box 1)
  - "The Board of Regents and the Lawyers Club: Regential Control Over Its Organization and Administration: 1924-1984" (Box 1)
  - Memorandum I: "Cook's Gift of the Lawyers Club Building" (Box 1)
  - Memorandum II: "Michigan Supreme Court Judicial Language Pertaining to the Status of the Lawyers Club" (Box 1)
  - Lawyers Club, correspondence regarding tax status project, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - William W. Cook and Cook gift, 3 folders (Box 1)
- Topical file
  - Blume, William W., correspondence with 1965-1978 (Box 1)
  - Canes of U-M law school students (Box 1)
  - Coalition for Responsible Prison Site Selection 1989-1991 (Box 1)
  - Detroit Income Tax Ordinance (Box 1)
  - Gaspar/Henshaw genealogy (Box 1)
  - Judge Advocate General and use of Law Quad during World War II (Box 1)
  - Kilgore, Sarah (Box 1)
  - Law School class of 1878 research, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Law School faculty biographies project (Box 1)
  - Law School student notebook study (Box 1)
  - Law School. Individuals Outside the US Receiving Law Degrees from the University of Michigan (Box 1)
  - Law School student costs and fees (Box 1)
  - Law School literary and debating societies, ca. 1960 (Box 1)
  - Law School finances, correspondence and research notes 1958 (Box 1)
  - Lincoln's thought (proposal to the National Endowment for the Humanities) 1975 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Income Tax legislation, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Michigan Property Tax Procedure, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Page, William Herbert, correspondence with and about (Box 1)
  - Quarles family (law school graduates) (Box 1)
  - Rockford College term papers 1933-1935 (Box 1)
  - St. Andrew's Episcopal Church activities and writings 1957-1963 (Box 1)
  - Stason, E. Blythe (memorandum on his deanship) (Box 1)
  - State Supreme Court records 1966, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Wright, L. Hart, miscellaneous, 5 folders (Box 2)
- Articles, Speeches, and other Writings
  - "The Bar on a Frontier: Wayne County, 1796-1836" (reprint) (Box 2)
  - "British Statutes in the Emergent Nations of Africa: 1844-1962" (photocopy of journal article) (Box 2)
  - "The lawyer on the frontier: Wayne County, 1796-1836" 1969 (Box 2)
  - "British Statutes in the Emergent Nations of North America: 1606-1949" (Box 2)
  - "Civil War Artifacts -- Their Travels from 317 Main Street to 101 West Main Street: 1865-1992" (Box 2)
  - "Frontier Justice: Wayne County 1796-1836" (Box 2)
  - "Henry Billings Brown: Michigan's Overlooked Associate Justice of the Supreme Court of the United States" (Box 2)
  - Laws in Force in the Territories of the United States: 1787-1912 (Box 2)
  - "Notes on the University Hospital: The Early Decades" (Box 2)
  - "Obligations of a State-Created Authority: Do They Constitute a Debt of the State?" Comment (Box 2)
  - "Professional Education Then and Now" (Box 2)
  - "Academic Appointments Held by Thomas M. Cooley" (Box 2)
  - "Contributions to Legal Literature 1859 and Forward," Introduction (Box 2)
  - "Elias Finley Johnson: 1861-1933" (Box 2)
  - "The First Hall of the University" (Box 2)
  - "The Initial Admission of the Negro Students to the University of Michigan" (Box 2)
  - "Law School Chronology: 1837-1987" (Box 2)
  - "The Law School of the University of Michigan 1859-1984 An Intellectual History"
    - Extended version (Box 2)
    - Reprint (Box 2)
  - "The Law School of the University of Michigan: Named Professorships" (Box 2)
  - "Miscellaneous Comments with Respect to the Deanship of E. Blythe Stason, 1939-1960" (Box 2)
  - "Student Conduct and Misconduct" (Box 2)
  - "The courthouses on Main Street, Waukesha County, Wisconsin, 1846-1959" 1969 (Box 2)
    (include copy of reprint of the article under the title "Two courthouses ..." 1971)
  - "Poor relief in Waukesha County, Wisconsin: 1846-1866" and revisions ca. 1969 (Box 2)
  - "The Waukesha County Jail-Building, Administration, Inmates: 1901-1904" 1978 (Box 2)
  - "International Law at Michigan: The first seventeen Decades" 1991 (Box 2)
  - "Bantam Sized Overview of Securities Regulations" by EB and L. Hart Wright (Box 2)
  - Poetry and miscellanea, 4 folders (Box 2)